export const questions =[
    {
        "question":"Another name for alkanes is acetics ?",
        "options":[
             "Both true and false",
             "False",
             "True",
             "None of the Above",
             "Maybe"
        ],
        "answer": "false"

    },
    {
        "question":"Chemistry of soap is known as  ?",
        "options":[
             "Soap reaction",
             "Saponification",
             "Steocheometry",
             "Electrolysis",
             "Thermodynamics"
        ],
        "answer": "Saponifiction "

    }, {
        "question":"what is the bond angle of alkanes ?",
        "options":[
             "180 degs",
             "50 degs",
             "80 degs",
             "109.5 degs",
             "10 degs"
],
        "answer": "109.5 degs"

    },
    {
        "question":"if you react alkanoic acid with and alkanol, what will be the resulting organic compound ?",
        "options":[
             "Ether",
             "Ester",
             "Ketone",
             "Nitrile",
             "Cocaine"
],
        "answer": "Ester"

    },
    {
        "question":"when alkanes are reacted with bromine water what will be the reactant ?",
        "options":[
             "Acid Hallide",
             "ketone",
             "Akyl Hallide",
             "No reaction",
             "Urea"
],
        "answer": "No reaction "

    },
    {
        "question": "Which molecule contains a carbon-carbon double bond?",
        "options": [
          "A. Ethane",
          "B. Ethene",
          "C. Ethyne",
          "D. Ethyl alcohol",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Ethene"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which product is obtained when chloromethane (or methyl chloride) is reduced?",
        "options": [
          "A. Ethane",
          "B. Ethene",
          "C. Methane",
          "D. Ethyne",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Methane"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which reacts explosively with methane?",
        "options": [
          "A. F2",
          "B. Cl2",
          "C. Br2",
          "D. I2",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. F2"
      },
      {
        "question": "By dehydration we mean, the removal of:",
        "options": [
          "A. Hydrogen",
          "B. Water",
          "C. Halogen",
          "D. Hydrogen halide",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Water"
      },
      {
        "question": "Ethane and ethyne can be differentiated by:",
        "options": [
          "A. Hydrogenation",
          "B. Bromine water",
          "C. Dilute alkaline aqueous solution of KMnO4",
          "D. Hydrohalogenation",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Bromine water"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is used for dehydrohalogenation?",
        "options": [
          "A. Br2, water",
          "B. Conc. H2SO4",
          "C. Al2O3",
          "D. Alcoholic KOH",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Alcoholic KOH"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which substance reacts with KMnO4 to produce oxalic acid?",
        "options": [
          "A. Ethane",
          "B. Ethene",
          "C. Ethyne",
          "D. Ethyl alcohol",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Ethyne"
      },
      {
        "question": "The reaction of alkyl halides takes place in the presence of:",
        "options": [
          "A. Al2O3 at 350 0C",
          "B. Conc. H2SO4 at 170 0C",
          "C. Zn (dust)",
          "D. Zn + HCl",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Zn + HCl"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which process produces an alkane?",
        "options": [
          "A. Combustion",
          "B. Hydration",
          "C. Dehydration",
          "D. Hydrogenation",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Hydrogenation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Does not react with aqueous solution of bromine:",
        "options": [
          "A. C2H6",
          "B. C2H4",
          "C. C2H2",
          "D. C3H6",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. C2H6"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following properties makes carbon unique in organic chemistry?",
        "options": [
          "A. Carbon forms only single bonds with other elements.",
          "B. Carbon can form stable chains and rings by bonding with itself.",
          "C. Carbon always forms ionic bonds with other elements.",
          "D. Carbon is less electronegative than hydrogen.",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Carbon can form stable chains and rings by bonding with itself."
      },
      {
        "question": "Identify the compound with an alcohol functional group.",
        "options": [
          "A. CH3-CH2-O-CH2-CH3",
          "B. CH3-CH2-NH2",
          "C. CH3-CH2-OH",
          "D. CH3-CO-CH3",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. CH3-CH2-OH"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following functional groups contains a carbon-oxygen double bond?",
        "options": [
          "A. Hydroxyl group",
          "B. Amine group",
          "C. Carbonyl group",
          "D. Ether group",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Carbonyl group"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct IUPAC name for the compound with the structure CH3CH2CH2OH?",
        "options": [
          "A. Ethanol",
          "B. Methanol",
          "C. Propanol",
          "D. Butanol",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Propanol"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the correct condensed structural formula for 2-methylbutane?",
        "options": [
          "A. CH3CH2CH2CH3",
          "B. CH3CH2CHCH3",
          "C. CH3CH2CH(CH3)CH3",
          "D. CH3CH2CH2CH2CH3",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. CH3CH2CH(CH3)CH3"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following describes resonance in organic molecules?",
        "options": [
          "A. The ability of molecules to shift between different structures.",
          "B. The presence of delocalized electrons in a molecule that can be represented by multiple equivalent Lewis structures.",
          "C. The phenomenon where molecules form different isomers based on the arrangement of atoms.",
          "D. The ability of carbon to form multiple bonds with hydrogen.",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. The presence of delocalized electrons in a molecule that can be represented by multiple equivalent Lewis structures."
      },
      {
        "question": "What type of isomerism is exhibited by 1-bromopropane and 2-bromopropane?",
        "options": [
          "A. Structural isomerism",
          "B. Geometric isomerism",
          "C. Optical isomerism",
          "D. Conformational isomerism",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Structural isomerism"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which type of organic reaction involves the replacement of one atom or group by another?",
        "options": [
          "A. Addition reaction",
          "B. Elimination reaction",
          "C. Substitution reaction",
          "D. Rearrangement reaction",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Substitution reaction"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is an example of a hydrocarbon with only single bonds?",
        "options": [
          "A. Alkene",
          "B. Alkane",
          "C. Alkyne",
          "D. Aromatic hydrocarbon",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Alkane"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the IUPAC name of the following compound: CH3CH2CH(CH3)CH2OH?",
        "options": [
          "A. 2-methyl-1-butanol",
          "B. 3-methyl-2-butanol",
          "C. 2-methyl-2-butanol",
          "D. 3-methyl-1-butanol",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 2-methyl-1-butanol"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the correct IUPAC name for the compound with the molecular formula CH3(CH2)4CHO?",
        "options": [
          "A. 1-hexanol",
          "B. Hexanal",
          "C. Hexanoic acid",
          "D. 1-hexene",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Hexanal"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following reagents can selectively oxidize primary alcohols to aldehydes without further oxidation to carboxylic acids?",
        "options": [
          "A. Jones reagent",
          "B. PCC (Pyridinium chlorochromate)",
          "C. Lindlar's catalyst",
          "D. Sodium borohydride",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. PCC (Pyridinium chlorochromate)"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the number of carbon atoms present in the simplest aldehyde and ketone?",
        "options": [
          "A. 1 and 1",
          "B. 1 and 3",
          "C. 2 and 2",
          "D. 2 and 3",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 2 and 2"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which property is not characteristic of carbonyl-containing compounds?",
        "options": [
          "A. High dipole moment",
          "B. High boiling point compared to hydrocarbons",
          "C. Poor solubility in water",
          "D. Ability to form hydrogen bonds with water",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Poor solubility in water"
      },
      {
        "question": "Ketones can be prepared by the oxidation of:",
        "options": [
          "A. Primary alcohols",
          "B. Secondary alcohols",
          "C. Tertiary alcohols",
          "D. Aldehydes",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Secondary alcohols"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
        "options": [
          "A. The C=O bond of carbonyls is short, strong and very polar",
          "B. The carbon of the carbonyl is electrophile while the oxygen is nucleophile",
          "C. The hydrogen on the α-carbon of a carbonyl is acidic",
          "D. All of the above",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. All of the above"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following methods results in the synthesis of carbonyls?",
        "options": [
          "A. Ozonolysis of alkenes",
          "B. Friedel-Crafts alkylation",
          "C. Reduction of alkynes",
          "D. None of the above",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Ozonolysis of alkenes"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the first step in a nucleophilic addition reaction on a carbonyl group under acidic conditions?",
        "options": [
          "A. Protonation of the oxygen of C=O",
          "B. Addition to oxygen of C=O",
          "C. Addition to carbon of C=O",
          "D. Nucleophilic attack",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Protonation of the oxygen of C=O"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following reactions results in the formation of an acetal from a carbonyl?",
        "options": [
          "A. Addition of hydrides",
          "B. Addition of water",
          "C. Addition of alcohols",
          "D. Addition of amines",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Addition of alcohols"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the definition of a chiral compound?",
        "options": [
          "A. An object that is superimposable on its mirror image",
          "B. A molecule with a carbon atom with 4 different substituents",
          "C. A molecule with a plane of symmetry",
          "D. An object that is non-superimposable on its mirror image",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. An object that is non-superimposable on its mirror image"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect?",
        "options": [
          "A. The specific rotation of 2 diastereomers has a different absolute value",
          "B. (+) in front of a chiral compound means that its absolute configuration is R",
          "C. A racemic mixture of a chiral compound contains equal amount of (+) and (-) compound",
          "D. The (+) and (-) stereoisomer of the same chiral compound will rotate polarized light equally but in opposite directions",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. (+) in front of a chiral compound means that its absolute configuration is R"
      },
      {
        "question": "How many chiral centers does the 2,4-dibromo-1,1,4-trimethylcyclohexane have?",
        "options": [
          "A. 0",
          "B. 1",
          "C. 2",
          "D. 3 or more",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 2"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following compound is chiral?",
        "options": [
          "A. 1-bromobutane",
          "B. 2-bromobutane",
          "C. 2-bromo-2-methylbutane",
          "D. 3-bromopentane",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 2-bromobutane"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the enantiomer of the (1S,3S)-1-bromo-3-methylcyclohexane?",
        "options": [
          "A. (1S,3R)-1-bromo-3-methylcyclohexane",
          "B. (1R,3S)-1-bromo-3-methylcyclohexane",
          "C. (1R,3R)-1-bromo-3-methylcyclohexane",
          "D. (1S,3S)-1-bromo-3-methylcyclohexane is not chiral",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. (1R,3R)-1-bromo-3-methylcyclohexane"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the correct IUPAC name for the linear alkane with the chemical formula C7H16?",
        "options": [
          "A. Heptanane",
          "B. Isoheptane",
          "C. Heptane",
          "D. Methylhexane",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Heptane"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an alkane, what do the terms primary, secondary, tertiary, and quaternary specifically refer to?",
        "options": [
          "A. Types of carbon chains",
          "B. The number of halogen atoms attached",
          "C. The degree of unsaturation",
          "D. The number of carbon atoms attached to a given carbon atom",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. The number of carbon atoms attached to a given carbon atom"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the IUPAC name of the alkane with the following structure: CH3-CH2-CH(CH3)-CH(CH3)2?",
        "options": [
          "A. Heptane",
          "B. 1-methylhexane",
          "C. 2,3-dimethylpentane",
          "D. 1,1,2-trimethylbutane",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 2,3-dimethylpentane"
      },
      {
        "question": "The process of separating a complex mixture of alkanes into simpler fractions based on boiling point is known as:",
        "options": [
          "A. Polymerization",
          "B. Cracking",
          "C. Halogenation",
          "D. Fractional distillation",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Fractional distillation"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which statement accurately describes the reactivity of alkanes?",
        "options": [
          "A. Alkanes are highly reactive due to the presence of functional groups",
          "B. Alkanes are generally unreactive under normal conditions",
          "C. Alkanes readily undergo substitution reactions but not addition reactions",
          "D. Alkanes are always involved in combustion reactions",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Alkanes are generally unreactive under normal conditions"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the alkyne addition reactions below involves an enol intermediate?",
        "options": [
          "A. Addition of hydrogen halide",
          "B. Hydroboration - Oxidation",
          "C. Hydration with HgSO4",
          "D. None of the above",
          "E. All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Hydration with HgSO4"
      },
      {
        "question": "The triple bond of an alkyne is made up of:",
        "options": [
          "A. 3 σ bonds",
          "B. 2 σ bonds + 1 π bond",
          "C. 1 σ bond + 2 π bonds",
          "D. 3 π bonds",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 1 σ bond + 2 π bonds"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the IUPAC name for the smallest member of the alkyne series with a carbon-carbon triple bond end position?",
        "options": [
          "A. Propyne",
          "B. Ethylene",
          "C. Ethyne",
          "D. Methane",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Ethyne"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the product of the electrophilic addition of one molecule of X2 to an alkyne?",
        "options": [
          "A. Geminal dihalide",
          "B. Vicinal dihalide",
          "C. Ethyne dihalide",
          "D. Trans dihalide",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Vicinal dihalide"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which reagent is typically used for the oxidative cleavage of alkynes to give carboxylic acids?",
        "options": [
          "A. Ozonolysis (O3)",
          "B. Hydrogenation (H2)",
          "C. Sodium amalgam (Na-Hg)",
          "D. Potassium carbonate (K2CO3)",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Ozonolysis (O3)"
      },
      {
        "question": "Alcohols that contain 5 hydorxyl groups are known as",
        "options": [
            "A. Monohydric alcohols",
            "B. Polyhydric alcohols",
            "C. Pentahydric alcohols",
            "D. Dihydric alcohols",
            "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Polyhydric alcohols"
      }

]